[
    {
        "ID": 350,
        "Question": "__________ has the advantage of flexibility, but the disadvantage of complexity.\na. Stack addressing\nb. Displacement addressing\nc. Direct addressing\nd. Register addressing",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Displacement addressing"
    },
    {
        "ID": 351,
        "Question": "For _________, the address field references a main memory address and the referenced register contains a positive displacement from that address.\na. indexing\nb. base-register addressing\nc. relative addressing\nd. all of the above",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "indexing"
    },
    {
        "ID": 352,
        "Question": "Indexing performed after the indirection is __________.\na. relative addressing\nb. autoindexing\nc. postindexing\nd. preindexing",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "postindexing"
    },
    {
        "ID": 353,
        "Question": "For the _________ mode, the operand is included in the instruction.\na. immediate\nb. base\nc. register\nd. displacement",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "immediate"
    },
    {
        "ID": 354,
        "Question": "The only form of addressing for branch instructions is _________ addressing.\na. register\nb. relative\nc. base\nd. immediate",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "immediate"
    },
    {
        "ID": 355,
        "Question": "Which of the following interrelated factors go into determining the use of the addressing bits?\na. number of operands\nb. number of register sets\nc. address range\nd. all of the above",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "all of the above"
    },
    {
        "ID": 356,
        "Question": "_________ is a principle by which two variables are independent of each other.\na. Opcode\nb. Orthogonality\nc. Completeness\nd. Autoindexing",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Orthogonality"
    },
    {
        "ID": 357,
        "Question": "The _________ was designed to provide a powerful and flexible instruction set within the constraints of a 16-bit minicomputer.\na. PDP-1\nb. PDP-8\nc. PDP-11\nd. PDP-10",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "PDP-11"
    },
    {
        "ID": 358,
        "Question": "The __________ byte consists of three fields: the Scale field, the Index field and the Base field.\na. SIB\nb. VAX\nc. PDP-11\nd. ModR/M",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "SIB"
    },
    {
        "ID": 359,
        "Question": "All instructions in the ARM architecture are __________ bits long and follow a regular format.\na. 8\nb. 16\nc. 32\nd. 64",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "32"
    },
    {
        "ID": 360,
        "Question": "__________ is a design principle employed in designing the PDP-10 instruction set.\na. Orthogonality\nb. Completeness\nc. Direct addressing\nd. All of the above",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "All of the above"
    },
    {
        "ID": 361,
        "Question": "The processor needs to store instructions and data temporarily while an instruction is being executed.\n(T/F)",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "T"
    },
    {
        "ID": 362,
        "Question": "The control unit (CU) does the actual computation or processing of data.\n(T/F)",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "F"
    },
    {
        "ID": 363,
        "Question": "Within the processor there is a set of registers that function as a level of memory above main memory and cache in the hierarchy.\n(T/F)",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "T"
    },
    {
        "ID": 364,
        "Question": "Condition codes facilitate multiway branches.\n(T/F)",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "T"
    },
    {
        "ID": 365,
        "Question": "The allocation of control information between registers and memory are not considered to be a key design issue.\n(T/F)",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "F"
    },
    {
        "ID": 366,
        "Question": "Instruction pipelining is a powerful technique for enhancing performance but requires careful design to achieve optimum results with reasonable complexity.\n(T/F)",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "T"
    },
    {
        "ID": 367,
        "Question": "The cycle time of an instruction pipeline is the time needed to advance a set of instructions one stage through the pipeline.\n(T/F)",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "T"
    },
    {
        "ID": 368,
        "Question": "A control hazard occurs when two or more instructions that are already in the pipeline need the same resource.\n(T/F)",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "F"
    },
    {
        "ID": 369,
        "Question": "One of the major problems in designing an instruction pipeline is assuring a steady flow of instructions to the initial stages of the pipeline.\n(T/F)",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "T"
    },
    {
        "ID": 370,
        "Question": "The predict-never-taken approach is the most popular of all the branch prediction methods.\n(T/F)",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "T"
    },
    {
        "ID": 371,
        "Question": "It is possible to improve pipeline performance by automatically rearranging instructions within a program so that branch instructions occur later than actually desired.\n(T/F)",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "T"
    },
    {
        "ID": 372,
        "Question": "Interrupt processing allows an application program to be suspended in order that a variety of interrupt conditions can be serviced and later resumed.\n(T/F)",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "T"
    },
    {
        "ID": 373,
        "Question": "An interrupt is generated from software and it is provoked by the execution of an instruction.\n(T/F)",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "F"
    },
    {
        "ID": 374,
        "Question": "While the processor is in user mode the program being executed is unable to access protected system resources or to change mode, other than by causing an exception to occur.\n(T/F)",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "T"
    },
    {
        "ID": 375,
        "Question": "The exception modes have full access to system resources and can change modes freely.\n(T/F)",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "T"
    },
    {
        "ID": 376,
        "Question": "__________ are a set of storage locations.\nA. Processors\nB. PSWs\nC. Registers\nD. Control units",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "ID": 377,
        "Question": "The ________ controls the movement of data and instructions into and out of the processor.\nA. control unit\nB. ALU\nC. shifter\nD. branch",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "ID": 378,
        "Question": "________ registers may be used only to hold data and cannot be employed in the calculation of an operand address.\nA. General purpose\nB. Data\nC. Address\nD. Condition code",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "ID": 379,
        "Question": "__________ are bits set by the processor hardware as the result of operations.\nA. MIPS\nB. Condition codes\nC. Stacks\nD. PSWs",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "ID": 380,
        "Question": "The _________ contains the address of an instruction to be fetched.\nA. instruction register\nB. memory address register\nC. memory buffer register\nD. program counter",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "ID": 381,
        "Question": "The _________ contains a word of data to be written to memory or the word most recently read.\nA. MAR \nB. PC\nC. MBR\nD. IR",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "ID": 382,
        "Question": "The ________ determines the opcode and the operand specifiers.\nA. decode instruction\nB. fetch operands\nC. calculate operands \nD. execute instruction",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "ID": 383,
        "Question": "_________ is a pipeline hazard.\nA. Control\nB. Resource\nC. Data\nD. All of the above",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "ID": 384,
        "Question": "A ________ hazard occurs when there is a conflict in the access of an operand location.\nA. resource\nB. data\nC. structural\nD. control",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "ID": 385,
        "Question": "A _________ is a small, very-high-speed memory maintained by the instruction fetch stage of the pipeline and containing the n most recently fetched instructions in sequence.\nA. loop buffer\nB. delayed branch\nC. multiple stream\nD. branch prediction",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "ID": 386,
        "Question": "The _________ is a small cache memory associated with the instruction fetch stage of the pipeline.\nA. dynamic branch\nB. loop table\nC. branch history table\nD. flag",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "ID": 387,
        "Question": "The _________ stage includes ALU operations, cache access, and register update.\nA. decode\nB. execute\nC. fetch\nD. write back",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "B"
    },
    {
        "ID": 388,
        "Question": "________ is used for debugging.\nA. Direction flag\nB. Alignment check\nC. Trap flag\nD. Identification flag",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "C"
    },
    {
        "ID": 389,
        "Question": "The ARM architecture supports _______ execution modes.\nA. 2\nB. 8\nC. 11\nD. 7",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "D"
    },
    {
        "ID": 390,
        "Question": "The OS usually runs in ________.\nA. supervisor mode\nB. abort mode\nC. undefined mode\nD. fast interrupt mode",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A"
    },
    {
        "ID": 391,
        "Question": "Microprogramming eases the task of designing and implementing the control unit and provides support for the family concept.\na. True\nb. False",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "ID": 392,
        "Question": "Pipelining is a means of introducing parallelism into the essentially sequential nature of a machine-instruction program.\na. True\nb. False",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "ID": 393,
        "Question": "The major cost in the life cycle of a system is hardware.\na. True\nb. False",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "ID": 394,
        "Question": "It is common for programs, both system and application, to continue to exhibit new bugs after years of operation.\na. True\nb. False",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "ID": 395,
        "Question": "Procedure calls and returns are not important aspects of HLL programs.\na. True\nb. False",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "ID": 396,
        "Question": "The register file is on the same chip as the ALU and control unit.\na. True\nb. False",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "ID": 397,
        "Question": "The register file employs much shorter addresses than addresses for cache and memory.\na. True\nb. False",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "ID": 398,
        "Question": "To handle any possible pattern of calls and returns the number of register windows would have to be unbounded.\na. True\nb. False",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "ID": 399,
        "Question": "Cache memory is a much faster memory than the register file.\na. True\nb. False",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "ID": 400,
        "Question": "The cache is capable of handling global as well as local variables.\na. True\nb. False",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "ID": 401,
        "Question": "When using graph coloring, nodes that share the same color cannot be assigned to the same register.\na. True\nb. False",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "False"
    },
    {
        "ID": 402,
        "Question": "With simple, one cycle instructions, there is little or no need for microcode.\na. True\nb. False",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "ID": 403,
        "Question": "Almost all RISC instructions use simple register addressing.\na. True\nb. False",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "ID": 404,
        "Question": "RISC processors are more responsive to interrupts because interrupts are checked between rather elementary operations.\na. True\nb. False",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "ID": 405,
        "Question": "Unrolling can improve performance by increasing instruction parallelism by improving pipeline performance.\na. True\nb. False",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "True"
    },
    {
        "ID": 406,
        "Question": "_________ determines the control and pipeline organization.\na. Calculation\nb. Execution sequencing\nc. Operations performed\nd. Operands used",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Execution sequencing"
    },
    {
        "ID": 407,
        "Question": "The Patterson study examined the dynamic behavior of _________ programs, independent of the underlying architecture.\na. HLL\nb. RISC\nc. CISC\nd. all of the above",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "HLL"
    },
    {
        "ID": 408,
        "Question": "_________ is the fastest available storage device.\na. Main memory\nb. Cache\nc. Register storage\nd. HLL",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Register storage"
    },
    {
        "ID": 409,
        "Question": "The first commercial RISC product was _________.\na. SPARC\nb. CISC\nc. VAX\nd. the Pyramid",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "the Pyramid"
    },
    {
        "ID": 410,
        "Question": "_________ instructions are used to position quantities in registers temporarily for computational operations.\na. Load-and-store\nb. Window\nc. Complex\nd. Branch",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Load-and-store"
    },
    {
        "ID": 411,
        "Question": "Which stage is required for load and store operations?\na. I\nb. E\nc. D\nd. all of the above",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "all of the above"
    },
    {
        "ID": 412,
        "Question": "A ________ instruction can be used to account for data and branch delays.\na. SUB\nb. NOOP\nc. JUMP\nd. all of the above",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "NOOP"
    },
    {
        "ID": 413,
        "Question": "The instruction location immediately following the delayed branch is referred to as the ________.\na. delay load\nb. delay file\nc. delay slot\nd. delay register",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "delay slot"
    },
    {
        "ID": 414,
        "Question": "A tactic similar to the delayed branch is the _________, which can be used on LOAD instructions.\na. delayed load\nb. delayed program\nc. delayed slot\nd. delayed register",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "delayed load"
    },
    {
        "ID": 415,
        "Question": "The MIPS R4000 uses ________ bits for all internal and external data paths and for addresses, registers, and the ALU.\na. 16\nb. 32\nc. 64\nd. 128",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "64"
    },
    {
        "ID": 416,
        "Question": "All MIPS R series processor instructions are encoded in a single ________ word format.\na. 4-bit\nb. 8-bit\nc. 16-bit\nd. 32-bit",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "32-bit"
    },
    {
        "ID": 417,
        "Question": "A _________ architecture is one that makes use of more, and more fine-grained pipeline stages.\na. parallel\nb. superpipelined\nc. superscalar\nd. hybrid",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "superpipelined"
    },
    {
        "ID": 418,
        "Question": "The R4000 can have as many as _______ instructions in the pipeline at the same time.\na. 8\nb. 10\nc. 5\nd. 3",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "8"
    },
    {
        "ID": 419,
        "Question": "SPARC refers to an architecture defined by ________.\na. Microsoft\nb. Apple\nc. Sun Microsystems\nd. IBM",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Sun Microsystems"
    },
    {
        "ID": 420,
        "Question": "The R4000 pipeline stage where the instruction result is written back to the register file is the __________ stage.\na. write back\nb. tag check\nc. data cache\nd. instruction execute",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "write back"
    },
    {
        "ID": 421,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "There is a tremendous variety of products, from single-chip microcomputers costing a few dollars to supercomputers costing tens of millions of dollars that can rightly claim the name \"computer\".\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 422,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The variety of computer products is exhibited only in cost.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 423,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Computer organization refers to attributes of a system visible to the programmer.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 424,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Changes in computer technology are finally slowing down.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 425,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The textbook for this course is about the structure and function of computers.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 426,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The number of bits used to represent various data types is an example of an architectural attribute.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 427,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Interfaces between the computer and peripherals is an example of an organizational attribute.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 428,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Historically the distinction between architecture and organization has not been an important one.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 429,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A particular architecture may span many years and encompass a number of different computer models, its organization changing with changing technology.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 430,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A microcomputer architecture and organization relationship is not very close.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 431,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Changes in technology not only influence organization but also result in the introduction of more powerful and more complex architectures.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 432,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The hierarchical nature of complex systems is essential to both their design and their description.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 433,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Both the structure and functioning of a computer are, in essence, simple.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 434,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A computer must be able to process, store, move, and control data.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 435,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "When data are moved over longer distances, to or from a remote device, the process is known as data transport.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 436,
        "Question": "rapid",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Computer technology is changing at a __________ pace.\nA. Slow\nB. Slow to medium\nC. Rapid\nD. Non-existent"
    },
    {
        "ID": 437,
        "Question": "architecture",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Computer _________ refers to those attributes that have a direct impact on the logical execution of a program.\nA. Organization\nB. Specifics\nC. Design\nD. Architecture"
    },
    {
        "ID": 438,
        "Question": "I/O mechanisms",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Architectural attributes include __________ .\nA. I/O mechanisms\nB. Control signals\nC. Interfaces\nD. Memory technology used"
    },
    {
        "ID": 439,
        "Question": "Organizational",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "_________ attributes include hardware details transparent to the programmer.\nA. Interface\nB. Organizational\nC. Memory\nD. Architectural"
    },
    {
        "ID": 440,
        "Question": "Architectural",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "It is a(n) _________ design issue whether a computer will have a multiply instruction.\nA. Architectural\nB. Memory\nC. Elementary\nD. Organizational"
    },
    {
        "ID": 441,
        "Question": "Organizational",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "It is a(n) _________ issue whether the multiply instruction will be implemented by a special multiply unit or by a mechanism that makes repeated use of the add unit of the system.\nA. Architectural\nB. Memory\nC. Mechanical\nD. Organizational"
    },
    {
        "ID": 442,
        "Question": "Hierarchical",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A __________ system is a set of interrelated subsystems.\nA. Secondary\nB. Hierarchical\nC. Complex\nD. Functional"
    },
    {
        "ID": 443,
        "Question": "Peripheral",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "An I/O device is referred to as a __________.\nA. CPU\nB. Control device\nC. Peripheral\nD. Register"
    },
    {
        "ID": 444,
        "Question": "Data communications",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "When data are moved over longer distances, to or from a remote device, the process is known as __________.\nA. Data communications\nB. Registering\nC. Structuring\nD. Data transport"
    },
    {
        "ID": 445,
        "Question": "Main memory",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The _________ stores data.\nA. System bus\nB. I/O\nC. Main memory\nD. Control unit"
    },
    {
        "ID": 446,
        "Question": "I/O",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The __________ moves data between the computer and its external environment.\nA. Data transport\nB. I/O\nC. Register\nD. CPU interconnection"
    },
    {
        "ID": 447,
        "Question": "System bus",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A common example of system interconnection is by means of a __________.\nA. Register\nB. System bus\nC. Data transport\nD. Control device"
    },
    {
        "ID": 448,
        "Question": "System interconnection",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A _________ is a mechanism that provides for communication among CPU, main memory, and I/O.\nA. System interconnection\nB. CPU interconnection\nC. Peripheral\nD. Processor"
    },
    {
        "ID": 449,
        "Question": "Registers",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "_________ provide storage internal to the CPU.\nA. Control units\nB. ALUs\nC. Main memory\nD. Registers"
    },
    {
        "ID": 450,
        "Question": "ALU",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The __________ performs the computer's data processing functions.\nA. Register\nB. CPU interconnection\nC. ALU\nD. System bus"
    },
    {
        "ID": 451,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The world's first general-purpose electronic digital computer was designed and constructed at The Ohio State University.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 452,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "John Mauchly and John Eckert designed the ENIAC.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 453,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The major drawback of the EDVAC was that it had to be programmed manually by setting switches and plugging and unplugging cables.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 454,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The IAS is the prototype of all subsequent general-purpose computers.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 455,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The IAS operates by repetitively performing an instruction cycle.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 456,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Backward compatible means that the programs written for the older machines can be executed on the new machine.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 457,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A vacuum tube is a solid-state device made from silicon.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 458,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Computers are classified into generations based on the fundamental hardware technology employed.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 459,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "System software was introduced in the third generation of computers.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 460,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A wafer is made of silicon and is broken up into chips which consists of many gates and/or memory cells plus a number of input and output attachment points.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 461,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "IBM's System/360 was the industry's first planned family of computers.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 462,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Intel's 4004 was the first chip to contain all of the components of a CPU on a single chip.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 463,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Designers wrestle with the challenge of balancing processor performance with that of main memory and other computer components.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 464,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The Intel x86 evolved from RISC design principles and is used in embedded systems.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 465,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A common measure of performance for a processor is the rate at which instructions are executed, expressed as billions of instructions per seconds (BIPS).\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 466,
        "Question": "ENIAC",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The _________ was the world's first general-purpose electronic digital computer.\nA. UNIVAC\nB. MARK IV\nC. ENIAC\nD. Hollerith's Counting Machine"
    },
    {
        "ID": 467,
        "Question": "World War II",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The Electronic Numerical Integrator and Computer project was a response to U.S. needs during _________.\nA. The Civil War\nB. The French-American War\nC. World War I\nD. World War II"
    },
    {
        "ID": 468,
        "Question": "Vacuum tubes",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The ENIAC used __________.\nA. Vacuum tubes\nB. Integrated circuits\nC. IAS\nD. Transistors"
    },
    {
        "ID": 469,
        "Question": "First",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The ENIAC is an example of a _________ generation computer.\nA. First\nB. Second\nC. Third\nD. Fourth"
    },
    {
        "ID": 470,
        "Question": "Control unit",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The __________ interprets the instructions in memory and causes them to be executed.\nA. Main memory\nB. Control unit\nC. I/O\nD. Arithmetic and logic unit"
    },
    {
        "ID": 471,
        "Question": "Words",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The memory of the IAS consists of 1000 storage locations called __________.\nA. Opcodes\nB. Wafers\nC. VLSIs\nD. Words"
    },
    {
        "ID": 472,
        "Question": "Instruction register",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The __________ contains the 8-bit opcode instruction being executed.\nA. Memory buffer register\nB. Instruction buffer register\nC. Instruction register\nD. Memory address register"
    },
    {
        "ID": 473,
        "Question": "Fetch cycle",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "During the _________ the opcode of the next instruction is loaded into the IR and the address portion is loaded into the MAR.\nA. Execute cycle\nB. Fetch cycle\nC. Instruction cycle\nD. Clock cycle"
    },
    {
        "ID": 474,
        "Question": "Transistors",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Second generation computers used __________.\nA. Integrated circuits\nB. Transistors\nC. Vacuum tubes\nD. Large-scale integration"
    },
    {
        "ID": 475,
        "Question": "Integrated circuit",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The __________ defines the third generation of computers.\nA. Integrated circuit\nB. Vacuum tube\nC. Transistor\nD. VLSI"
    },
    {
        "ID": 476,
        "Question": "Multicore",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The use of multiple processors on the same chip is referred to as __________ and provides the potential to increase performance without increasing the clock rate.\nA. Multicore\nB. GPU\nC. Data channels\nD. MPC"
    },
    {
        "ID": 477,
        "Question": "Pentium",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "With the __________, Intel introduced the use of superscalar techniques that allow multiple instructions to execute in parallel.\nA. Core\nB. 8080\nC. 80486\nD. Pentium"
    },
    {
        "ID": 478,
        "Question": "Speed metric",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The __________ measures the ability of a computer to complete a single task.\nA. Clock speed\nB. Speed metric\nC. Execute cycle\nD. Cycle time"
    },
    {
        "ID": 479,
        "Question": "All of the above",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "ARM processors are designed to meet the needs of _________.\nA. Embedded real-time systems\nB. Application platforms\nC. Secure applications\nD. All of the above"
    },
    {
        "ID": 480,
        "Question": "Clock tick",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "One increment, or pulse, of the system clock is referred to as a _________.\nA. Clock tick\nB. Cycle time\nC. Clock rate\nD. Cycle speed"
    },
    {
        "ID": 481,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "At a top level, a computer consists of CPU, memory, and I/O components.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 482,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The basic function of a computer is to execute programs.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 483,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Program execution consists of repeating the process of instruction fetch and instruction execution.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 484,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Interrupts do not improve processing efficiency.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 485,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "An I/O module cannot exchange data directly with the processor.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 486,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A key characteristic of a bus is that it is not a shared transmission medium.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 487,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Computer systems contain a number of different buses that provide pathways between components at various levels of the computer system hierarchy.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 488,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "In general, the more devices attached to the bus, the greater the bus length and hence the greater the propagation delay.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 489,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "It is not possible to connect I/O controllers directly onto the system bus.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 490,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The method of using the same lines for multiple purposes is known as time multiplexing.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 491,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Timing refers to the way in which events are coordinated on the bus.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 492,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "With asynchronous timing the occurrence of events on the bus is determined by a clock.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 493,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Because all devices on a synchronous bus are tied to a fixed clock rate, the system cannot take advantage of advances in device performance.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 494,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The unit of transfer at the link layer is a phit and the unit transfer at the physical layer is a flit.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 495,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A key requirement for PCIe is high capacity to support the needs of higher data rate I/O devices such as Gigabit Ethernet.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 496,
        "Question": "John von Neumann",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Virtually all contemporary computer designs are based on concepts developed by __________ at the Institute for Advanced Studies, Princeton.\nA. John Maulchy\nB. John von Neumann\nC. Herman Hollerith\nD. John Eckert"
    },
    {
        "ID": 497,
        "Question": "All of the above",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The von Neumann architecture is based on which concept?\nA. Data and instructions are stored in a single read-write memory\nB. The contents of this memory are addressable by location\nC. Execution occurs in a sequential fashion\nD. All of the above"
    },
    {
        "ID": 498,
        "Question": "Software",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A sequence of codes or instructions is called __________.\nA. Software\nB. Memory\nC. An interconnect\nD. A register"
    },
    {
        "ID": 499,
        "Question": "Instruction",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The processing required for a single instruction is called a(n) __________ cycle.\nA. Execute\nB. Fetch\nC. Instruction\nD. Packet"
    },
    {
        "ID": 500,
        "Question": "Hardware failure interrupt",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A(n) _________ is generated by a failure such as power failure or memory parity error.\nA. I/O interrupt\nB. Hardware failure interrupt\nC. Timer interrupt\nD. Program interrupt"
    },
    {
        "ID": 501,
        "Question": "Program interrupt",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A(n) _________ is generated by some condition that occurs as a result of an instruction execution.\nA. Timer interrupt\nB. I/O interrupt\nC. Program interrupt\nD. Hardware failure interrupt"
    },
    {
        "ID": 502,
        "Question": "All of the above",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The interconnection structure must support which transfer?\nA. Memory to processor\nB. Processor to memory\nC. I/O to or from memory\nD. All of the above"
    },
    {
        "ID": 503,
        "Question": "System bus",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A bus that connects major computer components (processor, memory, I/O) is called a __________.\nA. System bus\nB. Address bus\nC. Data bus\nD. Control bus"
    },
    {
        "ID": 504,
        "Question": "Address lines",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The __________ are used to designate the source or destination of the data on the data bus.\nA. System lines\nB. Data lines\nC. Control lines\nD. Address lines"
    },
    {
        "ID": 505,
        "Question": "Data bus",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The data lines provide a path for moving data among system modules and are collectively called the _________.\nA. Control bus\nB. Address bus\nC. Data bus\nD. System bus"
    },
    {
        "ID": 506,
        "Question": "Protocol",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A __________ is the high-level set of rules for exchanging packets of data between devices.\nA. Bus\nB. Protocol\nC. Packet\nD. QPI"
    },
    {
        "ID": 507,
        "Question": "Lane",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Each data path consists of a pair of wires (referred to as a __________) that transmits data one bit at a time.\nA. Lane\nB. Path\nC. Line\nD. Bus"
    },
    {
        "ID": 508,
        "Question": "Transaction layer",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The _________ receives read and write requests from the software above the TL and creates request packets for transmission to a destination via the link layer.\nA. Transaction layer\nB. Root layer\nC. Configuration layer\nD. Transport layer"
    },
    {
        "ID": 509,
        "Question": "All of the above",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The TL supports which of the following address spaces?\nA. Memory\nB. I/O\nC. Message\nD. All of the above"
    },
    {
        "ID": 510,
        "Question": "Routing",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The QPI _________ layer is used to determine the course that a packet will traverse across the available system interconnects.\nA. Link\nB. Protocol\nC. Routing\nD. Physical"
    },
    {
        "ID": 511,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "No single technology is optimal in satisfying the memory requirements for a computer system.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 512,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A typical computer system is equipped with a hierarchy of memory subsystems, some internal to the system and some external.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 513,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "External memory is often equated with main memory.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 514,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The processor requires its own local memory.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 515,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Cache is not a form of internal memory.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 516,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The unit of transfer must equal a word or an addressable unit.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 517,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Both sequential access and direct access involve a shared read-write mechanism.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 518,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "In a volatile memory, information decays naturally or is lost when electrical power is switched off.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 519,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "To achieve greatest performance the memory must be able to keep up with the processor.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 520,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Secondary memory is used to store program and data files and is usually visible to the programmer only in terms of individual bytes or words.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 521,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The L1 cache is slower than the L3 cache.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 522,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "With write back updates are made only in the cache.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 523,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "It has become possible to have a cache on the same chip as the processor.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 524,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "All of the Pentium processors include two on-chip L1 caches, one for data and one for instructions.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 525,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Cache design for HPC is the same as that for other hardware platforms and applications.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 526,
        "Question": "Location",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "__________ refers to whether memory is internal or external to the computer.\nA. Location\nB. Access\nC. Hierarchy\nD. Tag"
    },
    {
        "ID": 527,
        "Question": "Bytes",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Internal memory capacity is typically expressed in terms of _________.\nA. Hertz\nB. Nanos\nC. Bytes\nD. LOR"
    },
    {
        "ID": 528,
        "Question": "Unit of transfer",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "For internal memory, the __________ is equal to the number of electrical lines into and out of the memory module.\nA. Access time\nB. Unit of transfer\nC. Capacity\nD. Memory ratio"
    },
    {
        "ID": 529,
        "Question": "Sequential access",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "\"Memory is organized into records and access must be made in a specific linear sequence\" is a description of __________.\nA. Sequential access\nB. Direct access\nC. Random access\nD. Associative"
    },
    {
        "ID": 530,
        "Question": "Direct access",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "individual blocks or records have a unique address based on physical location with __________.\nA. Associative\nB. Physical access\nC. Direct access\nD. Sequential access"
    },
    {
        "ID": 531,
        "Question": "Access time",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "For random-access memory, __________ is the time from the instant that an address is presented to the memory to the instant that data have been stored or made available for use.\nA. Memory cycle time\nB. Direct access\nC. Transfer rate\nD. Access time"
    },
    {
        "ID": 532,
        "Question": "Memory cycle time",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The ________ consists of the access time plus any additional time required before a second access can commence.\nA. Latency\nB. Memory cycle time\nC. Direct access\nD. Transfer rate"
    },
    {
        "ID": 533,
        "Question": "Disk cache",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A portion of main memory used as a buffer to hold data temporarily that is to be read out to disk is referred to as a _________.\nA. Disk cache\nB. Latency\nC. Virtual address\nD. Miss"
    },
    {
        "ID": 534,
        "Question": "Tag",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A line includes a _________ that identifies which particular block is currently being stored.\nA. Cache\nB. Hit\nC. Tag\nD. Locality"
    },
    {
        "ID": 535,
        "Question": "Direct mapping",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "__________ is the simplest mapping technique and maps each block of main memory into only one possible cache line.\nA. Direct mapping\nB. Associative mapping\nC. Set associative mapping\nD. None of the above"
    },
    {
        "ID": 536,
        "Question": "Write through",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "When using the __________ technique all write operations made to main memory are made to the cache as well.\nA. Write back\nB. LRU\nC. Write through\nD. Unified cache"
    },
    {
        "ID": 537,
        "Question": "Split cache",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The key advantage of the __________ design is that it eliminates contention for the cache between the instruction fetch/decode unit and the execution unit.\nA. Logical cache\nB. Split cache\nC. Unified cache\nD. Physical cache"
    },
    {
        "ID": 538,
        "Question": "Execution unit",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The Pentium 4 _________ component executes micro-operations, fetching the required data from the L1 data cache and temporarily storing results in registers.\nA. Fetch/decode unit\nB. Out-of-order execution logic\nC. Execution unit\nD. Memory subsystem"
    },
    {
        "ID": 539,
        "Question": "Miss",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "In reference to access time to a two-level memory, a _________ occurs if an accessed word is not found in the faster memory.\nA. Miss\nB. Hit\nC. Line\nD. Tag"
    },
    {
        "ID": 540,
        "Question": "Virtual addresses",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A logical cache stores data using __________.\nA. Physical addresses \nB. Virtual addresses\nC. Random addresses\nD. None of the above"
    },
    {
        "ID": 541,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The basic element of a semiconductor memory is the memory cell.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 542,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A characteristic of ROM is that it is volatile.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 543,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "RAM must be provided with a constant power supply.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 544,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The two traditional forms of RAM used in computers are DRAM and SRAM.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 545,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A static RAM will hold its data as long as power is supplied to it.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 546,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Nonvolatile means that power must be continuously supplied to the memory to preserve the bit values.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 547,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The advantage of RAM is that the data or program is permanently in main memory and need never be loaded from a secondary storage device.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 548,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Semiconductor memory comes in packaged chips.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 549,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "All DRAMs require a refresh operation.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 550,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A number of chips can be grouped together to form a memory bank.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 551,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "An error-correcting code enhances the reliability of the memory at the cost of added complexity.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 552,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "DRAM is much costlier than SRAM.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 553,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "RDRAM is limited by the fact that it can only send data to the processor once per bus clock cycle.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 554,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The prefetch buffer is a memory cache located on the RAM chip.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 555,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The SRAM on the CDRAM cannot be used as a buffer to support the serial access of a block of data.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 556,
        "Question": "All of the above",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Which properties do all semiconductor memory cells share?\nA. They exhibit two stable states which can be used to represent binary 1 and 0\nB. They are capable of being written into to set the state\nC. They are capable of being read to sense the state\nD. All of the above"
    },
    {
        "ID": 557,
        "Question": "RAM",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "One distinguishing characteristic of memory that is designated as _________ is that it is possible to both to read data from the memory and to write new data into the memory easily and rapidly.\nA. RAM\nB. ROM\nC. EPROM\nD. EEPROM"
    },
    {
        "ID": 558,
        "Question": "All of the above",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Which of the following memory types are nonvolatile?\nA. Erasable PROM\nB. Programmable ROM\nC. Flash memory\nD. All of the above"
    },
    {
        "ID": 559,
        "Question": "SRAM",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "In a _________, binary values are stored using traditional flip-flop logic-gate configurations.\nA. ROM\nB. SRAM\nC. DRAM\nD. RAM"
    },
    {
        "ID": 560,
        "Question": "ROM",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A __________ contains a permanent pattern of data that cannot be changed, is nonvolatile, and cannot have new data written into it.\nA. RAM\nB. SRAM\nC. ROM\nD. Flash memory"
    },
    {
        "ID": 561,
        "Question": "Flash memory",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "With _________ the microchip is organized so that a section of memory cells are erased in a single action.\nA. Flash memory\nB. SDRAM\nC. DRAM\nD. EEPROM"
    },
    {
        "ID": 562,
        "Question": "Hard errors",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "__________ can be caused by harsh environmental abuse, manufacturing defects, and wear.\nA. SEC errors \nB. Hard errors\nC. Syndrome errors\nD. Soft errors"
    },
    {
        "ID": 563,
        "Question": "Soft errors",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "_________ can be caused by power supply problems or alpha particles.\nA. Soft errors\nB. AGT errors\nC. Hard errors \nD. SEC errors"
    },
    {
        "ID": 564,
        "Question": "SDRAM",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The _________ exchanges data with the processor synchronized to an external clock signal and running at the full speed of the processor/memory bus without imposing wait states.\nA. DDR-DRAM\nB. SDRAM\nC. CDRAM\nD. None of the above"
    },
    {
        "ID": 565,
        "Question": "DDR-DRAM",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "________ can send data to the processor twice per clock cycle.\nA. CDRAM\nB. SDRAM\nC. DDR-DRAM\nD. RDRAM"
    },
    {
        "ID": 566,
        "Question": "DDR2",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "__________ increases the data transfer rate by increasing the operational frequency of the RAM chip and by increasing the prefetch buffer from 2 bits to 4 bits per chip.\nA. DDR2\nB. RDRAM\nC. CDRAM\nD. DDR3"
    },
    {
        "ID": 567,
        "Question": "DDR3",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "________ increases the prefetch buffer size to 8 bits.\nA. CDRAM\nB. RDRAM\nC. DDR3\nD. All of the above"
    },
    {
        "ID": 568,
        "Question": "200 to 600",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Theoretically, a DDR module can transfer data at a clock rate in the range of __________ MHz.\nA. 200 to 600\nB. 400 to 1066\nC. 600 to 1400\nD. 800 to 1600"
    },
    {
        "ID": 569,
        "Question": "800 to 1600",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A DDR3 module transfers data at a clock rate of __________ MHz.\nA. 600 to 1200\nB. 800 to 1600\nC. 1000 to 2000\nD. 1500 to 3000"
    },
    {
        "ID": 570,
        "Question": "Buffer",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The ________ enables the RAM chip to preposition bits to be placed on the data bus as rapidly as possible.\nA. Flash memory\nB. Hamming code\nC. RamBus\nD. Buffer"
    },
    {
        "ID": 571,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Magnetic disks are the foundation of external memory on virtually all computer systems.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 572,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "During a read or write operation, the head rotates while the platter beneath it stays stationary.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 573,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The width of a track is double that of the head.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 574,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "There are typically hundreds of sectors per track and they may be either fixed or variable lengths.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 575,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A bit near the center of a rotating disk travels past a fixed point slower than a bit on the outside.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 576,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The disadvantage of using CAV is that individual blocks of data can only be directly addressed by track and sector.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 577,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A removable disk can be removed and replaced with another disk.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 578,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The head must generate or sense an electromagnetic field of sufficient magnitude to write and read properly.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 579,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The transfer time to or from the disk does not depend on the rotation speed of the disk.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 580,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "RAID is a set of physical disk drives viewed by the operating system as a single logical drive.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 581,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "RAID level 0 is not a true member of the RAID family because it does not include redundancy to improve performance.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 582,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Because data are striped in very small strips, RAID 3 cannot achieve very high data transfer rates.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 583,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The SSDs now on the market use a type of semiconductor memory referred to as flash memory.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 584,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "SSD performance has a tendency to speed up as the device is used.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 585,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Flash memory becomes unusable after a certain number of writes.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 586,
        "Question": "the glass substrate",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Greater ability to withstand shock and damage, improvement in the uniformity of the magnet film surface to increase disk reliability, and a significant reduction in overall surface defects to help reduce read-write errors, are all benefits of ___________.\na. magnetic read and write mechanisms\nb. platters\nc. the glass substrate\nd. a solid state drive"
    },
    {
        "ID": 587,
        "Question": "gaps",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Adjacent tracks are separated by _________.\na. sectors\nb. gaps\nc. pits\nd. heads"
    },
    {
        "ID": 588,
        "Question": "sectors",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Data are transferred to and from the disk in __________.\na. tracks\nb. gaps\nc. sectors\nd. pits"
    },
    {
        "ID": 589,
        "Question": "512",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "In most contemporary systems fixed-length sectors are used, with _________ bytes being the nearly universal sector size.\na. 64\nb. 128\nc. 256\nd. 512"
    },
    {
        "ID": 590,
        "Question": "constant angular velocity",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Scanning information at the same rate by rotating the disk at a fixed speed is known as the _________.\na. constant angular velocity\nb. magnetoresistive\nc. rotational delay\nd. constant linear velocity"
    },
    {
        "ID": 591,
        "Question": "CAV",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The disadvantage of _________ is that the amount of data that can be stored on the long outer tracks is only the same as what can be stored on the short inner tracks.\na. SSD\nb. CAV\nc. ROM\nd. CLV"
    },
    {
        "ID": 592,
        "Question": "nonremovable",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A __________ disk is permanently mounted in the disk drive, such as the hard disk in a personal computer.\na. nonremovable\nb. movable-head\nc. double sided\nd. removable"
    },
    {
        "ID": 593,
        "Question": "double sided",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "When the magnetizable coating is applied to both sides of the platter the disk is then referred to as _________.\na. multiple sided\nb. substrate\nc. double sided\nd. all of the above"
    },
    {
        "ID": 594,
        "Question": "cylinder",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The set of all the tracks in the same relative position on the platter is referred to as a _________.\na. floppy disk\nb. single-sided disk\nc. sector\nd. cylinder"
    },
    {
        "ID": 595,
        "Question": "access time",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The sum of the seek time and the rotational delay equals the _________, which is the time it takes to get into position to read or write.\na. access time\nb. gap time\nc. transfer time\nd. constant angular velocity"
    },
    {
        "ID": 596,
        "Question": "RAID",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "__________ is the standardized scheme for multiple-disk database design.\na. RAID\nb. CAV\nc. CLV\nd. SSD"
    },
    {
        "ID": 597,
        "Question": "1",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "RAID level ________ has the highest disk overhead of all RAID types.\na. 0\nb. 1\nc. 3\nd. 5"
    },
    {
        "ID": 598,
        "Question": "Blu-ray DVD",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A _________ is a high-definition video disk that can store 25 Gbytes on a single layer on a single side.\na. DVD\nb. DVD-R\nc. DVD-RW\nd. Blu-ray DVD"
    },
    {
        "ID": 599,
        "Question": "Constant linear velocity (CLV)",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "________ is when the disk rotates more slowly for accesses near the outer edge than for those near the center.\na. Constant angular velocity (CAV)\nb. Magnetoresistive\nc. Constant linear velocity (CLV)\nd. Seek time"
    },
    {
        "ID": 600,
        "Question": "lands",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The areas between pits are called _________.\na. lands\nb. sectors\nc. cylinders\nd. strips"
    },
    {
        "ID": 601,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A set of I/O modules is a key element of a computer system.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 602,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "An I/O module must recognize one unique address for each peripheral it controls.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 603,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "I/O channels are commonly seen on microcomputers, whereas I/O controllers are used on mainframes.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 604,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "It is the responsibility of the processor to periodically check the status of the I/O module until it finds that the operation is complete.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 605,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "With isolated I/O there is a single address space for memory locations and I/O devices.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 606,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A disadvantage of memory-mapped I/O is that valuable memory address space is used up.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 607,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The disadvantage of the software poll is that it is time consuming.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 608,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "With a daisy chain the processor just picks the interrupt line with the highest priority.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 609,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Bus arbitration makes use of vectored interrupts.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 610,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The rotating interrupt mode allows the processor to inhibit interrupts from certain devices.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 611,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "Because the 82C55A is programmable via the control register, it can be used to control a variety of simple peripheral devices.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 612,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "When large volumes of data are to be moved, a more efficient technique is direct memory access (DMA).\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 613,
        "Question": "T",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "An I/O channel has the ability to execute I/O instructions, which gives it complete control over I/O operations.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 614,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A multipoint external interface provides a dedicated line between the I/O module and the external device.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 615,
        "Question": "F",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A Thunderbolt compatible peripheral interface is no more complex than that of a simple USB device.\n(T/F)"
    },
    {
        "ID": 616,
        "Question": "I/O module",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The _________ contains logic for performing a communication function between the peripheral and the bus.\nA. I/O channel\nB. I/O module\nC. I/O processor\nD. I/O command"
    },
    {
        "ID": 617,
        "Question": "keyboard/monitor",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The most common means of computer/user interaction is a __________.\nA. keyboard/monitor\nB. mouse/printer\nC. modem/printer\nD. monitor/printer"
    },
    {
        "ID": 618,
        "Question": "control and timing",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The I/O function includes a _________ requirement to coordinate the flow of traffic between internal resources and external devices.\nA. cycle\nB. status reporting\nC. control and timing\nD. data"
    },
    {
        "ID": 619,
        "Question": "I/O channel",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "An I/O module that takes on most of the detailed processing burden, presenting a high-level interface to the processor, is usually referred to as an _________.\nA. I/O channel\nB. I/O command\nC. I/O controller\nD. device controller"
    },
    {
        "ID": 620,
        "Question": "I/O controller",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "An I/O module that is quite primitive and requires detailed control is usually referred to as an _________.\nA. I/O command\nB. I/O controller\nC. I/O channel\nD. I/O processor"
    },
    {
        "ID": 621,
        "Question": "write",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The _________ command causes the I/O module to take an item of data from the data bus and subsequently transmit that data item to the peripheral.\nA. control\nB. test\nC. read\nD. write"
    },
    {
        "ID": 622,
        "Question": "control",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The ________ command is used to activate a peripheral and tell it what to do.\nA. control\nB. test\nC. read\nD. write"
    },
    {
        "ID": 623,
        "Question": "Cycle stealing",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "________ is when the DMA module must force the processor to suspend operation temporarily.\nA. Interrupt\nB. Thunderbolt\nC. Cycle stealing\nD. Lock down"
    },
    {
        "ID": 624,
        "Question": "fly-by",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The 8237 DMA is known as a _________ DMA controller.\nA. command\nB. cycle stealing\nC. interrupt\nD. fly-by"
    },
    {
        "ID": 625,
        "Question": "DisplayPort",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "________ is a digital display interface standard now widely adopted for computer monitors, laptop displays, and other graphics and video interfaces.\nA. DisplayPort\nB. PCI Express\nC. Thunderbolt\nD. InfiniBand"
    },
    {
        "ID": 626,
        "Question": "Common transport",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The ________ layer is the key to the operation of Thunderbolt and what makes it attractive as a high-speed peripheral I/O technology.\nA. cable\nB. application\nC. common transport\nD. physical"
    },
    {
        "ID": 627,
        "Question": "physical",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The Thunderbolt protocol _________ layer is responsible for link maintenance including hot-plug detection and data encoding to provide highly efficient data transfer.\nA. cable\nB. application\nC. common transport\nD. physical"
    },
    {
        "ID": 628,
        "Question": "application",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "The ________ contains I/O protocols that are mapped on to the transport layer.\nA. cable\nB. application\nC. common transport\nD. physical"
    },
    {
        "ID": 629,
        "Question": "target channel adapter",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A ________ is used to connect storage systems, routers, and other peripheral devices to an InfiniBand switch.\nA. target channel adapter\nB. InfiniBand switch\nC. host channel adapter\nD. subnet"
    },
    {
        "ID": 630,
        "Question": "router",
        "Choices": [],
        "Answer": "A ________ connects InfiniBand subnets, or connects an InfiniBand switch to a network such as a local area network, wide area network, or storage area network.\nA. memory controller\nB. TCA\nC. HCA\nD. router"
    }
]